Edgar David Garcia Torres

TORONTO, ON. M5T-1Z9. |+1 647 5706403| edgardavidgt@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/edgar-garcia-to/

SUMMARY

Computer programmer and electronic engineer interested in working as a software developer. Experience developing Web applications with frameworks with Angular, React.js, Next.js ASP.NET including RESTful API. Experience in installation, troubleshooting and debugging industrial automated systems.

SKILLS

Programming languages: C, C++, C#, Java, Cobol, Python, JavaScript, typescript, SQL, html, CSS.

Web development: Express.js Angular, React.js, Next.js, ASP.NET, RESTful API, jQuery

Databases: MongoDB, Postgre, SQL Server, ORACLE SQL. **Platforms:** UNIX, Linux, Windows, MAC, IBM-I Systems.

Technologies: GitHub, TCP/IP. Node.js

Tools: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse IDE, SQL Server, LabView, MATLAB, Wireshark

EXPERIENCE

TOLindo Deliveries, Toronto, ON - Front end developer OCTOBER 2022 - Today

- Create user interfaces based on given designs and implement its functionalities using react.js framework.
- Maintain and update the existing TOLindo Website.

Beumer Group, Bogota, Colombia - Electronic maintenance supervisor FEBRUARY 2019 – JANUARY 2021

- Lead technical teams from 4 to 8 members to perform maintenance of baggage handling system at Bogota's international airport.
- Maintenance of control systems (PLC Siemens), industrial networks and microelectronic systems.
- **Key achievement**: Reprogramming fire doors' functioning to increase their lifespan.
- Key achievement: Generate SQL server queries to generate maintenance statistics for analysis.

Av Villas Bank, Bogota-Colombia - Software developer (Internship) JUNE 2016 – JANUARY 2017

• Implementation of banking applications for the business portal using ETL, C# with .NET, Visual Studio, SQL Server, and transaction processing with Cobol in IBM-I system Z/390.

EDUCATION

Seneca college Diploma - Computer programming Diploma GPA: 3.8/4

JANUARY 2021 - AUGUST 2022, TORONTO-ONTARIO

El Bosque university - Bachelor's degree electronic Engineering

JANUARY 2011 - NOVEMBER 2016, BOGOTA-COLOMBIA

Central university Diploma – Programable Logic Controllers and industrial communication networks.

AUGUST 2018 - OCTOBER 2018, BOGOTA-COLOMBIA

AWARDS

Mention of honor: For research work presented to apply for the degree of Electronic Engineer called:

"Wireless control for guitar analog effects", Developed using LabVIEW and Microcontrollers programmed in C language.